[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
is
[Music]
cool all right ladies and gentlemen i'm
here with bradley roth uh of the not
most people podcast
uh i think you guys are really gonna
like this episode bradley you want to
give me a little bit of your background
just kind of a bio of what you do how
you got here what's going on in your
world
yeah i'll try and keep it short but my
i got here is pretty indirect i started
out in the fitness industry growing up
that's who i was i was sports working
out that's kind of all i knew how i
defined myself and then
got through college i did that for about
five years training groups people
one-on-one from there i dabbled in
real estate network marketing a couple
other things i wasn't sure
kind of what i wanted to do and then
my fiancee
as a nurse and we just had to do the
travel nurse thing
for a little while and so i had to find
something that was location independent
very quickly and i kind of dove head
first into
entrepreneurship started with social
media
marketing social media management
transitioned to facebook ads
transitioned to
chat bots and this was all over the
course of probably three years and then
during that time i kind of knew for a
while that
i wanted to
long term be in the
coaching and personal development space
that was kind of what i was really
passionate about and i felt like i could
really help people a lot and
i
i had this concept for a podcast well
actually it wasn't for a podcast just a
concept for like a brand not most people
i had it probably two or three years ago
i didn't know what i was going to do
with it and
i got into this kind of mastermind group
called the rta syndicate and
i've been listening to podcasts but
everyone i was listening to had like big
time personal brands big time businesses
you know hundreds of thousands of
followers and stuff like that so
i didn't think like a normal person like
me
could podcast right and then i got into
this group and i found out a ton of
people had podcasts i was like okay this
is interesting
and
i went on a couple
as a guest the first one i was nervous i
was like i don't know about this
and
uh but then i went on another one and it
went really well like an hour later
we're still flowing it's going great got
off that this was actually last november
and right after that episode i said okay
not most people is gonna be a podcast
thanks and
i said i was gonna launch by january
took me until about mid march to get up
and going
and my plan was to kind of do this as on
the side as a little passion project and
then continue to work on my marketing
business
eventually once i kind of saw that
through or sold it or whatever then i
would allow myself to move into kind of
the coaching space where i wanted to go
but the podcast got off to kind of a
good start got a lot of good feedback i
think my marketing experience really
helped with that
and
that kind of was assigned to me that
like this is where you this area is
where you need to be spending more of
your time
so i kind of followed my and
kind of dialed things down on the
marketing business and have been ramping
things up in the coaching side
so now i have the podcast to help other
people
launch their podcasts
with an online course and then
i've kind of decided to specialize or
niche down into relationship coaching so
for people who are in long-term
relationships uh particularly
entrepreneurs high performers that's who
i kind of like to
work with spend time with and so
yeah it's been kind of a weird uh
weird way to get here but
that's where we are now so working on
kind of those two things in tandem
they're not directly related but there's
some overlap so it kind of works
right yeah yeah i know it i could
totally see how it all coincides
together um and kind of leads you on
your journey to where you are now so you
talked about the uh the mastermind can
you tell me a little bit more about that
what was this situation explain it for
someone who hasn't even heard of
masterminds or any sort of these
get-togethers
yeah so
a couple big-time entrepreneurs i can't
remember how i initially found him by
andy furcella
he for many years had the world's
number one entrepreneurship podcast and
it's still ranked i think top five or so
something like that but i had been
listening to that for a while
uh back
two three years ago that's probably the
first podcast i really got into
and then him and uh a partner
or another kind of big figure at my left
who's also very well known
to get together and kind of create
a mastermind that was about
i mean arte in latin basically means
like excellence
so
the goal is to kind of
it's business
focused but it's also kind of like
everything in life like everyone in
there you know you're trying to
get your body and mind and fitness right
it's not a bunch of bro marketing
tactics it's principles it's like stuff
that
you know there's so much of this kind of
guru
fake
pro marketing stuff out there especially
coming from the marketing space like i
see it all the time and
uh
you know it's kind of all like anti that
and so uh they opened up this mastermind
and the first year they did it was like
60 grand a year and you had to be doing
a million dollars in your business and
stuff like that so i was like okay i'll
put that on like the
three to five year vision board and
then i found out this past year that
they had actually kind of restructured
it to where
you know it was still a decent
investment but nothing near that um
and so
it was like you know three four hundred
dollars a month and you had to apply to
get in and so i applied to this and i
got in and i was i mean at the time it
was definitely a stretch for me and i
was like man i've never really had a
monthly commitment to anything like that
you know and
there's about 2 000 people in it but i
got in there and they do kind of private
one-on-one calls a few times a month
with andy and ed and sometimes they'll
bring in guests but then you have the
facebook community of like a couple of
thousand other kind of like-minded
entrepreneur individuals and
so it's just been really powerful over
the last year made like so many
connections and it's kind of hard to
like
i think back i'm like man who did i talk
to or hang out with before i joined that
group you know and
you know it's important because
if you're an entrepreneur and like right
now i'm pretty much a solopreneur i work
at home it's like
it gets lonely sometimes you know so
it's really important to
connect with other like-minded people
who
you know who get it who are going to
push you to be better and stuff like
that so
um i mean there's all kinds of
groups and programs and stuff like that
nowadays but that one's been really huge
for me
yeah i imagine it to be incredibly
fulfilling to
kind of be hustling on your own in this
whole environment and it obviously kind
of separates you and your old friends i
noticed that same sort of thing just
just naturally you know not in a bad way
it's all love in a lot of ways
but you just start to gravitate towards
different interests and different ways
of having conversations and i imagine
being around the the other guys or other
people who are kind of the same mindset
they want growth they want you know
prosperity and self-actualization for
their own life
they you know being around them and
being able to speak on that level a lot
of the time i imagine that would be
incredibly helpful uh that reminds me
too of the uh i heard you mentioned one
of the other podcasts and i think you
might have told me on the phone
uh you went to a tony robbins event so
while we're right here you want to
describe your experience at the tony
robbins event it's definitely been
something that i've always wanted to go
to i've i've watched so many i mean i've
listened to that guy for hours and hours
and hours very inspiring love the guy so
how was your experience with with the
tony robbins event
it was awesome i mean i kind of found
tony uh you know most people find him
through his events or youtube or his
audio courses or something like that i
found him through
uh one of his books awaken the giant
within which is a pretty well known book
and
i read that i think it was back 2017.
i was reading that and because i was
dealing with some living beliefs you
know still am of course but i was like
what do i read to to
improve on this and a lot of people
suggest that books i'm like all right
let's tell you i've heard of this guy
but i don't know anything about him i
was reading that book and as i'm reading
this book it's just like light bulb
moment after light bulb moment after
light bulb moment like i was like man
now i understand why i do this i
understand why people do this and i
understand
why this has held me back and why i have
this and like just all these things like
crazy and uh
so like that book alone changed my life
but then i read the book and
i told my girlfriend i'm like you know
like this book's been amazing i was like
i started looking into his uh events a
little bit you know because i started
looking him up i was like what's what
else does he have and found his
adventure like a big thing i've never
even heard of his events before that
somehow uh and then we watched
together we watched the netflix
documentary i'm not your guru
which you might have seen
and then after that
my girlfriend's like okay i kind of i
kind of get it the events look kind of
cool
and then she surprised me
christmas of 2017 with tickets to upw
which is
that's awesome yeah yeah super cool i
did not see that coming and
it was like upw is his main four day
event you know it's like 10 000 people
four days like 15 hour days like it's
you know it's pretty nuts and uh hosted
in like a hockey stadium usually this
one was in san jose california
so march of 2018 we go there and
we walk in and like you walk into this
place and it's like
culture shock like everyone in there is
like all pumped up you know like exactly
what you'd expect from like a
motivational kind of seminar thing right
like what do we get ourselves into like
my fiance is like
i'm about to turn around and walk out of
here
you know but like it's all like in a
good way and then i was like you know
what i'm just going in with an open mind
just go go with it and see what happens
because i think if you go in with
expectations or whatever that can kind
of
change the experience so we went in and
like by the end of day one
they break you so far out of your shell
like doing
crazy uh icebreakers with like strangers
and
you know dancing and hugging and like
all this like stuff that you're like why
why am i doing this
like
i don't get it but then
by day two and three like you
you there's no other place that you
won't want to be and it's like it's the
most fun you'll have in your life
surprisingly like people think oh it's a
seminar like you sit and you listen to
powerpoints it's like no it's like very
involved very active and
um
you're constantly like they're keeping
the energy up and there's a lot of
reasons and science behind it too but
it creates the emotional space to have a
lot of kind of breakthroughs you know
and
left that event and
i swear for like six months afterwards
like i was just on fire like i had so
much momentum i lost a bunch of weight
right away i was like signing clients
they left and right there like i didn't
even know how like it was just i don't
know and then that also kind of really
set me
like i had been started to read and get
into personal development a little bit
but after that event is when it really
took off and i started
diving in hard on that stuff because
i mean you go and it's like yeah it's
great and you get pumped up and stuff
like that but there's also a lot of
really deep psychology work that you do
during it that like
again
builds on those light bulb moments that
i was having before
so
just uh
yeah that was that was super powerful
and then we ended up actually going and
we crewed one of those events about six
months later where we were like
volunteering we helped oh no that was a
whole nother side of that experience
yeah yeah dude that sounds awesome um
yeah it's on my list of eventuals to to
attend is a tony robbins event i always
think they look absolutely fascinating
thinking about what it did
what it did for you i mean the first day
especially it sounds like it really took
your identity and just shook it you know
just kind of like made you really step
out of your shell made you step out of
your own habits and your your moods and
emotions and your preconceived ideas
about that um and then it took you know
a couple days after that to kind of
not necessarily i'm sure it was feeding
you a lot of information but almost kind
of tapping into information that you
already knew about yourself kind of
feeding the right sides of yourself and
i think uh
you know i think a lot of times we're
able to do this with the internet
nowadays like podcasts and youtube
videos um i went i mean i went through
tons of times where i'm just watching
way too many youtube videos and it it'll
send you you would listen to podcasts on
youtube it sends you to someone's book
and you're reading their book and you
know there'd be there'd be times weeks
and months at a time where i would go
through kind of that same yeah you had
your six months of just high energy
momentum i feel like i was able to kind
of obtain that in certain rollercoaster
ways with with youtube and podcasts and
audio books and such um
so where what do you see as like
like what is really going on here is is
it as simple as that like how would you
explain it bradley so this this
stripping of our identity and kind of a
revamping of who we think ourselves to
be like how could um you know not most
people people desiring this how could
they kind of achieve this or lean into
it or kind of search for it in the ways
that that you and me a little bit have
found
wow i mean that's really that's like a
major kind of can of worms question like
there's a lot of different things that
go into that but yeah i would say
i i think the whole world would be
vastly improved in every way if people
just learned a little bit about kind of
how the mind works right they learned a
little bit about
beliefs and dug into why they have
certain beliefs and
understanding their behaviors like one
of his one of tony's main frameworks
probably one of his most well known
things is the six human needs
and there's six human needs that
everybody
has universally
the first four are called the needs of
the personality
and those four everyone finds a way to
meet those needs either healthily or
unhealthily whether they recognize it or
not the last two are the needs of the
soul and that's what leads to kind of
fulfillment so the first four are
certainty
uncertainty or variety
significance
and love and connection and those four
needs everyone finds some way to meet
those needs
right and then the last two which lead
to actual fulfillment are growth and
contribution
and so everyone finds a way to meet
those first four and so like you could
look at anyone's behavior
and
or like i can now that i understand
those
those needs and
uh i can look at anyone's behavior and
say oh they're doing it because
they're trying to meet this need
right he's doing this this person's
being a bully because
they're trying to get significance in
their life
you know or they're trying to get love
and connection at the same time from
their friends who are going to think
they're cool right
and so a lot of times you're meeting
multiple needs at a time if you're
meeting more than three needs at a time
it's very likely that whatever it is
you're doing to do that becomes an
addiction
and so
it's really easy like once you have
an understanding of that framework to
say okay
here's where i'm here's why i'm doing
this this bad habit that i can't break
it's meeting this need
and so now how do i find a more healthy
way to meet that need
right and so you're able to kind of like
reverse engineer all of and understand
all of your behaviors or same for anyone
else like i can look at almost anyone
else and
what they're doing or not doing i could
say oh yeah they're doing that to meet
this need they're doing that to meet
that need and
so just like frameworks like that to
understand yourself and others it's like
man if people had just a very baseline
understanding of that like
the world would be such a different
place
yeah yeah i i totally agree i i think
about this moment when you first
right at the beginning if you kind of
have been living some sort of
unconsciously where you're not really
realizing oh i'm just meeting a need or
oh i'm trying to get that thing i don't
actually need that oh i'm just trying to
feel this way or whatever we're trying
to obtain and get and uh hold on to
that that moment when we notice it i
feel like you know part of our ego gets
in the way and blocks it out and it's
like no that's not you and it ignores it
or or it hurts you know it hurts to look
at the the places within us where we are
inadequate or um
where we're doing things we're like dang
i just ate another whole bag of chips
you know
like here i go again i didn't want to do
that i told myself i was going to have a
quarter of it whatever it is
so
what what do you what do you think about
that moment right there where we first
notice it that little piece of awareness
because i think that's a really defining
you can either you know shear away from
it look away from it or you can say huh
there i am doing that thing again what
what is it that i'm trying to get
yeah i mean i just you nailed it like
awareness is step one like if you don't
have awareness then
you can't fix anything if you're not
aware of it right and so
again this basic understanding starts to
build that awareness and like you'll so
you'll notice things a little bit but
then like
the more aware
you become
the more like the faster you can
catch yourself and analyze yourself and
fix the problem right and that's why
like you hear about meditation and
creating awareness because when you have
awareness then you are in more in
control
so
yeah creating like that basic awareness
that understanding is definitely
step one and most people just go through
life and they are completely unaware of
why they do things or why
they can't break certain patterns right
like a lot of people
will
pick up a behavior as a child to
get love from their parents or
um
their friends
so as a kid someone who's very loud and
complains a lot and that sort of thing
gets them attention from their parents
whether it's good or not
right and then
20 years later that person could still
be exhibiting that same behavior because
they learned when they were a kid that
that's how they get love and attention
is by being loud and obnoxious or
complaining or something like that and
so we continue to
carry on these
behaviors that
served us back then but no longer serve
us
right but if we're not aware then
there's no there's no way we're gonna
change
right
um or
let's say your
parents
like your dad
really really wanted you to get good
grades
and like
he'd either
be really mad or disappointed if you
didn't or he would you know he'd be
super happy if you didn't obviously like
you want love from your dad and so
that can turn someone into like a super
high achiever
who you know but then that may turn them
into kind of a workaholic and they think
that as an adult that the more they work
and more their more their love they're
gonna get but
it probably doesn't work that way
to a degree and so it's just like
all these patterns are kind of like if
we can
rewind and go back into our past and
figure out where they originated
and which ones are still serving us
which ones aren't
then yeah that's where that awareness
kicks in and allows us to say okay
here's what i need to change here's how
i can get another way i can meet that
need you know that's more healthy and
that sort of thing
yeah yeah brilliant man i really like
that do you have a meditation practice
yourself or do you find yourself um
teaching or recommending a certain type
of meditation or way of bringing
awareness to your clients
that's a good question i think
i don't think there's a
one-size-fits-all for it um
i struggle with meditation for sure i
i go through bouts where i'm real
consistent and then i'll go through
you know a phase where i'm not really
doing it much same same yeah
i could tell the difference um
i find for me i can't just do like a
silent meditation like my internal
dialogue is like a thousand miles an
hour at all times
so
uh whereas like you know some people
like at this at tony robbins events or
whatever else like if they do some kind
of guided thing like a lot of people can
get really into it like emotionally
connected quickly and it's like
takes me forever if at all to be able to
do that and like shut off that internal
dialogue so for me
uh
it is pretty difficult to kind of
silence that inner voice sometimes or
you know you don't want to try and
control it too much i think i'm always
trying to maybe control it a little much
but
anyways when it comes to meditation
i definitely need guided if anything um
and then
one thing again that tony taught is that
if you get yourself
physically
high like high energy state
like breathing heart or whatever
and then
all of that with some sort of meditation
or visualization you're allowed to you
can go much deeper so you have to go
low
and uh so that definitely helps i know
like if i am in a low energy state you
know i just woke up i'm kind of tired
drowsy whatever and then i go and i try
to
uh meditate it just it doesn't work as
well as if i you know
uh
throw on a high energy song for a couple
minutes or go for a walk or something
before you know and then i'm able to get
into it more but
another thing for me is
meditation visuals it comes down to
being present right
and getting
all those things that are going through
our minds at all times about the stuff
we got to do later or
things were stressed about or whatever
kind of silencing those
that's what it's really about and that's
you know so
it's cool to sit there and you know
breathe in breathe out that kind of
stuff but for me what i found to
actually be the most effective is to go
for a walk
like just out in nature and so
almost every day
it's really hot right now it's like 110
degrees and i got to go for a walk
because that's what i do each day right
now and i'm also doing a
kind of a 75 hard mental toughness
challenge um
but
i found the walks for me are super
beneficial
because when you get away from your
computer you go outside
it just forces you to kind of be present
and it doesn't happen right away like if
you go for a five or ten minute walk it
might not do the trick but if you go for
a 30-40 minute walk i guarantee by the
time you get back your head's going to
be a lot clearer
and so i've almost used that as like an
active form of meditation and getting
present and
yeah and depends on the day some days if
i'm
my gears are really turning too much and
i need to slow it down i'll go just
silent like no headphones or anything
uh if i want to some days if i want to
refocus i'll throw on a podcast
other days if i want to bring my energy
up if i'm feeling low energy i'll put on
music
and so i kind of use that walk it gets
you moving
physically it you know forces you to be
aware of your surroundings where you're
wherever you're at
and uh i found that to be really
powerful and really helpful
for me
yeah no i think that's i feel like walks
are massively underrated for that i mean
they can really get you especially
nowadays you know a lot of times we're
working on the computer we're working at
home we're sitting on our own smells for
a long time you know getting outside
just getting some fresh air getting some
temperature
some vitamin d you know
waving to your neighbors getting present
stretching your eyes too you know it's
like this this small thing but i i
imagine that the effects on our eyesight
and the way that we see um suddenly
within the last you know 20 25 years
just being on screen so much has
definitely changed from looking all
around and trying to appear for for prey
and and uh
in in predator uh
but uh
yeah so so
certainly going for a walk greatly
underrated i highly recommend it i agree
with you bradley um hey when it comes to
uh when it comes to fitness so obviously
just going for a walk
absolutely anything is so much better
than doing completely nothing so that i
always tell people like hey if you can't
get a workout in get a stretch and like
fall over out of your chair and roll
around for 10 minutes that's better than
absolutely nothing if you if you if you
can't drink any water like try to drink
half a cup water whatever it is that you
can get in um when it comes to fitness
do you have like
i mean do you have any blanket
statements that you that you like to
apply or making people kind of think
differently about fitness about their
physical body and how it really relates
to our mental body what do you have in
this realm
because i know you're a personal trainer
too as well before this so yeah yeah
there's there's a whole lot that can go
a whole lot of ways we can go with that
as well uh
but what you said about the walk is
important because something like a walk
like let's talk about habits in general
trying to instill new habits
like you go to
the gym on new year's and it's packed
two weeks later it's empty
why is that because people
try to
make like instant massive changes and
it's not sustainable and it's not fun
and your willpower is finite and it's
gonna
drop out all right so if you're trying
to go from couch potato to like
i'm gonna go run two miles every day
which i hear people try and do all the
time
you know it's like i'll give me ten to
one eyes like you're gonna be back on
the couch in a few weeks you know so
something like a walk is something that
like anyone can do
[Music]
right like that's if you a book i really
love is atomic habits i recommend it all
the time and james clear right james yep
james clear and uh one of the
biggest principles is to make it easy
right so instead of saying okay i'm
gonna go run five miles a day say okay
i'm gonna go to the gym for 10 minutes
like anyone can go to the gym for 10
minutes right but like once you're there
and once you're doing it you're probably
going to stay a little bit longer right
so it's just like getting yourself to
begin and take that first step and take
action
often leads to more action and so
making it easy like again if we're
talking about like if you're trying to
go from kind of
you're starting at a
non-active or not consistently working
out and you're trying to make that a new
habit or improve
something like that walk is a great
place to start because
for me
even some days like if i don't make it
to the gym
which right now i have to because this
challenge i'm doing but generally it's
like if i don't make it to the gym i'm
like okay at least i walked at least i
moved my body today
you know and at least you know because
the body's not made to be sedentary
and so we think that
rest is you know rest is important
recovery is important for sure
but
um
just moving makes such a difference
especially again we're sedentary all day
i got a standing desk so i like to stand
up sit down
during the day back and forth
um
yeah
there's there's a lot of
i guess one of the things would be
there's the other extreme where people
work out workout workout and they never
recover and they don't really
recovery and
people think that when you work out
you
are in better shape right after
no you're actually in worse shape right
after you work out because you just
broke down your body and the only way
you actually get better is by
rebuilding it stronger
see people who lift weights like seven
days a week and there's ways to do it
you know body different body splits and
intensity levels and stuff like that but
a lot of people think if they just go go
go and just pound themselves into the
ground that that's going to force more
adaptation and it's like well if you're
constantly breaking down you're not
giving your body a chance to
build back up and so you see a lot of
people
and i did this for a while too it's like
you'll go to the gym and you'll lift and
then you like look in the mirror right
after you're like
is there a difference like did it make a
difference and it's like
i noticed for me if i work out really
hard for a few days and i'm feeling
pretty beat up and sore
i'm gonna notice the difference in how i
look two to three days later once i've
recovered and rebuilt
so if i'm feeling like really sore i'm
like
and i'm like i'm sore like i should look
a little bit better and like you can you
can almost tell if you're low body fat
you can kind of tell those slight
changes but
um
i know that okay in a couple days my
muscles are going to look a lot fuller
than they are now you know
so giving that time to like
understanding that it's actually the
rebuilding and the recovery and the
refeeding that is going to actually make
you better
right right
are you still um are you still doing any
sort of crossfit like what are what are
your workouts typically like i mean
obviously everything's pretty crazy
since covid that's just we're all just
figuring out different ways to do
everything but i uh i have definitely
found i was a weightlifter for a long
time and i tried to do
a decent amount of cardio but as far as
any sort of crossfit movement um like
dancing zumba any sort of those like
constantly moving practices kind of new
to me now that i've been using
kettlebells i really enjoy kind of a
more primitive swinging around um you
know flexing a lot of different areas of
your body getting really stable a lot of
the core effort i like a lot of that now
um so what what's what's your workouts
now you do crossfit or what do you do
i do yeah i've been
i've been doing crossfit pretty much off
and on for the last like 10 plus years
and
i find that every time i kind of get
away from it i always end up finding my
way back uh
somehow like i took
i took a year off during covet just
because
uh i actually got injured
a little bit and so i decided to take
some time off and then gyms were closed
for a while and so i just kind of
ended up taking about a year off but
then i got back to it uh this past
spring and it's like
it's like falling in love with it again
uh
it's
it's interesting i will say that
crossfit is
it's not a franchise it's an affiliate
and so every gym is gonna have a very
different experience
and so
a lot of people will go to one gym and
think that's
what all crossfit is and it's like no
you can go to like two gyms that are
like down the street from each other and
they can be
totally different programming totally
different coaching style totally
different
competition level like you name it and
so
crossfit is a very kind of individual
like or gym thing
so something to be conscious of so
anyone who's like looking to get into it
i would say go to two or three different
gyms and see which one feels right for
you
but right now i'm doing
my daily walks of at least 45 minutes
right now uh because that's the part of
the challenge that i'm doing
which uh right now in arizona it's like
110 degrees today so yeah man
those can be uh
quite a workout in themselves you know
but then i'm also doing crossfit
probably four days a week right now and
i find for me
if i'm doing
more than that i start to feel pretty
beat up right
but that's going to be different for
everyone because i'm
i'm like ultra competitive like i get in
there and like at the end of each
workout i'm like that one guy who's like
dead laying on the floor you know nice
beyonce always makes fun of me for it
but
leave it all leave it all there man yeah
so i mean like i i go like 95 100
most of the time even though i go in and
i say oh today i'm just gonna like try
and finish and
whatever like i said that yesterday and
i went in and i was like
absolutely crushed after yesterday dude
it feels so good you feel so your mind
is so quiet you're like you feel like
you really won won that battle that was
internal you know
yeah i mean when you're when you're
going through something like crossfit or
something really intense where you're
like i just i've got to get through this
and that's that's the only thing on your
mind right now it forces you to think
about nothing else and to be totally
present and so that's what i love it's
like i
i'm working here all day i'm like all
right i gotta i'm going to crossfit and
it's like by the end of that class none
of the other stuff outside stuff is on
my mind it's just that because it was
you know it forces you to do that yeah
so but there are people who like if you
go to crossfit
and you're
i don't wanna say a lower level athlete
but if you're not like a hardcore like
competitive athlete you know because
because the more in shape people are
the more ability they have to really
push themselves really far you know in
terms of intensity level and so
if you're not
you know dying on the floor like me
every time like you could probably go
six days a week and i know a lot of
people who do and they're fine
you know so it it's really kind of an
individual thing but right now i'm doing
probably four days of crossfit
seven days of walking and those other
i have to do two workouts a day right
now so
those other days i'll do something kind
of light you know
bodybuilding style curls or something in
the living room you know nothing crazy
some mobility work which i used to do a
lot more of uh which is another thing
that
a lot of people ignore that is super
super essential is that mobility work
definitely
if you're not staying mobile and you're
building muscle like your muscles get
tight
uh i see so many people who neglected it
and they got shoulder issues
pain
all over the place again we're sitting
all day so it's like you go to the gym
and
you know i'm guilty of this lately like
you work out real hard you get sore and
then you go sit all day and just stiffen
up in these unnatural positions and want
the links to another so one thing that i
was really good about for a long time
uh
was doing mobility work and it paid off
big time because i've seen a lot of guys
you know a lot of guys like to go in and
they like to bench a lot
and your shoulders get super tight and
like when your shoulders get tight then
your back starts to round
and then that leads to a whole host of
other issues down the chain and so
just
you know
getting up throughout the day again we
talked about movement but doing some
stretches doing
whatever before and after your workout
like staying because
right now a lot of people want to go
hard you know when you're in your 20s
you're in your 30s you're like i want to
get in great shape i want big muscles i
want this and that
but
for the last probably 30 plus years of
your life what's going to be more
important to you the size of your biceps
or if you can like move comfortably and
be injury
right the long term
mobility is probably more important you
know so it's great to
man every so often i'll do like a little
bit of yoga and it's like
a wake-up call i'm like yes sir
for someone who's like i'm an athlete
yoga is like oh you know i don't need to
do that that's girl stuff whatever right
but yeah and it's
you're like oh okay i need to
focus a little bit more on my mobility
dude 100 i'm always encouraging people
i'm always telling everybody like have
you stretched today what are you doing
without stretching you got to get some
movement in
and especially that like before workout
before workout i stretch before i run i
stretch
i'm actually in the slow process of
getting my yoga teacher certification i
just kind of stumbled across yoga a few
years back
i was a lifter before and so it totally
like changed my body in the way that i
think about about my body a little less
bro lifting a little more union with
with the body and mind
i was actually thinking about too
bradley when you were talking about uh
kind of just going to the gym and giving
it your all um just
going in like you're not thinking about
these other things you basically took
the other things of your day the the
things that need to be taken care of and
you shelfed them um i can really see how
that's meditative to just be completely
here here's what i'm doing this one
thing is i'm working out i'm put i'm
giving it my all um and it's kind of
it's kind of like meditation you know
you you have your one thing you're
focusing on your breath let's say and if
anything else comes in oh i got that
meeting in 14 hours or whatever i've got
this whatever going on you just say no
i'm not worried about that right now you
keep it on the shelf that's kind of what
this one pointed focus of meditation is
and i think there's a lot of value in
doing that for your workouts as well um
because i find i'll kind of go back and
forth in between and tell me what you
think about this for kind of our modern
culture i kind of go back and forth
between
i will have those times where i'm in it
i've got my playlist going i'm like i'm
here if my phone goes off i'm not going
to answer it if i get a text i'm not
going to answer i'm not thinking about
anything else my workout then i'll also
have times where i'm very passively
listening and working out i have a
podcast on i'm kind of not sweating as
much maybe i'm doing some slow
stretching maybe i'm doing just like
some you know mess around the dumbbells
15 pounds 20 pounds
um what what do you think about this
difference between passive working out
passive listening to two things and then
this full-on i'm here i'm in it
i'm working
i would say it's a it's kind of an
individual thing like some people
i did it for a while like kind of the
bodybuilding style working out like you
go in you got your headphones and you're
just tunnel visions on your pre-workout
and you're you're doing your thing and
then
other people
need a group
to really kind of hit higher intensities
and so i think
for a lot of people
uh the groups are really powerful i know
for me they are like i
i'll try and do crossfit on my own like
at home
and
i could do a workout at home and then
i'll go and do it in the class it could
be the same exact workout i will be far
faster with the class
right and
you also warm up more you don't take
those shortcuts that you might when
you're on your own like when you're when
you're on your own and you're like oh
you tend to kind of like shorten the
warm-up and that mobility stuff that
we're talking about but when you're in
the group and everyone's doing here like
okay
well everyone's doing it so
like we're doing that that's what we're
doing and so
i find for me the group is
super powerful and
especially because everyone has their
own thing with working out like i
i'm actually a naturally pretty lazy
person when it comes to working out i
just am very competitive and so like
post college post sports crossfit is
like where i get my competition
and so i go and it's like each day it's
like okay i'm gonna i'm gonna try and
beat this guy or that guy or i'm gonna
i'm gonna try and beat this time you
know so sometimes you're competing
against someone else sometimes you're
competing against yourself
and
that's what really works and for me and
pushes me for other people
you know they like the social aspect of
the group you know going and being able
to see their friends you know that's
like that's i think one of the main
things that led to crosstalk growing so
quickly like it did was that community
and that culture right whereas if you go
to like kind of a big globo gym and you
got your headphones on and that sort of
thing it's not really a social thing
it's like you're kind of there it's you
and you get in you get out
so
i think it's individual to everyone but
i would recommend trying both
uh
because that group
for me and also
another thing i love about it is you
know i was a trainer for years and so i
know how to program and write workouts
and stuff like that
which is a blessing and a curse because
when i'm writing for someone else
it's pretty easy but if i'm trying to
program for myself
i overthink the heck out of it
this should i be doing that
and it's like the more you know the more
variables you take in and then your mind
starts like
and then you end up
uh analysis by paralysis
whereas now i'm the coach and it's like
i coach those classes that i'm taking
now but i love being able to just show
up here's the workout i don't have to
think about what i'm gonna do
and again it just helps with kind of
turning that mind off and and just it
can be just about getting the work done
whereas
you know if you're following a specific
program you got a personal trainer you
have a specific sports related or
bodybuilding or whatever type goal
and that individual might be better kind
of individual style
so you got to find out what works for
you but i found there to be several main
benefits of being in that group for me
yeah definitely the analysis paralysis
definitely rings rings true to me it's
the knowledge is power ignorance is
bliss you know it's there's all these
wonderful amazing different ways you can
work out there's so many different
choices there's all these different
plans you can follow which one do you
want to do today and so many options but
i i think i'm with you i like that
option of just
go in there and the thing they have
written on the board that's what you're
doing or the thing that that teacher is
teaching that's what you're doing like
you're just here to work and push
yourself otherwise they got the rest of
it taken care of i think that's
incredibly valuable
um
the uh
as far as i want to jump to a little bit
more of your podcast so what have you
what have you learned so far you're how
many episodes in are you you're
uh getting close to 30.
getting close to 30. so how have you
changed from you know episode one or
even before episode or even beings even
all the way back from being someone who
might not even see themselves as a
podcaster that's you already mentioned
it's like
um how has it changed you basically from
then until now
and it's been huge like
i don't know if i mentioned it but
growing up i was like
i was homeschooled for a while
and so i ended up going to school from
like eighth grade through high school
right
and before that i'd never like spoke in
front of a class or
done a presentation or anything so like
eighth grade through high school even
through college like
that thought of speaking in front of
other people scared the crap out of me
like i wouldn't sleep for weeks i'd have
extreme anxiety i'd get up there my
voice would shake i'd sweat it was it
was bad uh
i had to take a public speaking class in
college
for some reason i was required to be a
trainer
i think they gave me a c because they
felt bad and
so i got out and i knew that
more than anything i wanted to coach
crossfit classes like that i was
obsessed with it back then
and i knew i was gonna have to
be able to command a group in a class
and be loud and that sort of thing
so i got out and i went i was basically
i hounded the owner of the gym that i
wanted to work at for like months and
it's like all right we'll give you an
internship
and go from there
and he's like
we love how enthusiastic you are we know
you know your stuff but
we were concerned
about if you can really teach class like
commander class and i was too but i was
like you know what i'm gonna do it i'm
gonna figure it out
and uh it took a long time
uh a lot of people
at the gym
when i first started coaching they're
probably like oh this kid's not gonna
he's not gonna make it you know because
i was very quiet i was very unsure
and i started with uh
kind of assisting coaching
where they'd have a
main coach and i was kind of there
helping and then they kind of switched
roles where i was leading the class but
i had another coaches like back up and
eventually i was coaching my own classes
and then you know two three years in i
was finally like
super comfortable i could do it in my
sleep you know so that that experience
helped a lot
but then
another level of like
are you gonna put out content and be a
podcaster like even a year or two ago i
would have said like no way you're nuts
like
uh i couldn't stand the sound of my
voice played back to me
right
i sound so nasally and flat and low in
it i was like i can't there's no way and
uh
i went on those podcasts i had this
concept
i was like you know what i just i gotta
get over it because i was like the
things that i want to do in my life are
going to require me to get past that and
be able to speak and love that love that
and so
i kind of gained that leverage on myself
but i started the podcast back in march
the first episode was a solo episode
kind of explaining the concept of the
podcast and then
i mean i
basically wrote out the entire script to
read a word for word and that sort of
thing tried to make it sound natural
and once i got over that
that was
that was a big kind of step and then
for the most part it's been guest
interviews and so part of my strategy
early on
was and this is you know important for
anyone starting a podcast as i said you
know what i'm new at this i haven't done
a lot of speaking so my first guest i'm
going to make sure i have people on that
are going to make it really easy for me
so people who have done a lot of
speaking who can carry a conversation
who are dynamic high energy so that i
can basically
i don't have to carry it you know what i
mean and so i had my first few guests on
where exactly that they made it super
easy
and so that really helped me kind of
gain some confidence early on
and i'd still in those beginning
episodes and it feels like forever ago
but it's only been
marches what four months five months
i would i would really really prepare
hard in the beginning
and i would have all these kind of
specific questions that i would kind of
like check them off one by one and like
do it that way
i wouldn't really
go off on
much on my own wasn't really free flow i
was kind of like very mechanical with it
and over time especially as i started to
get a lot like positive feedback and
stuff like that now it's like okay
i look up a little bit about this person
10 minutes i write some bullet points
kind of a few areas i want to cover and
then it's just like free flow and we go
so in the course of like 20 to 25
episodes
it's completely changed like i get on
there now i'm like all right this is fun
i'm relaxed like we're gonna let's let's
roll and see where it goes versus like
in the beginning it was like
all right i gotta have my questions
ready i gotta know all this and
you know if i can't stumble here or like
if i go off on a tangent like i'm afraid
to do that so it's really evolved very
very fast you know so it's amazing if
you kind of jump in and take action
how quickly you can improve in those
areas yeah right i totally resonate with
all of that i've definitely changed my
approach as i've advanced and become a
better podcast house and been able to
listen to my own voice back in my own
head and uh you know you notice all of
your
if you're neurotic at all to listen to
and edit your own podcast it's just it's
just evil um
but uh i really like what you were
talking about um
you said something basically i knew that
i had to do it um or i knew that i had
to grow through whatever basically
finding something that makes you
uncomfortable and then still moving at
it or or using that as a place to push i
think that's incredibly valuable can you
expand on that a little bit
yeah it's just if i didn't really want
to become
a crossfit coach i probably still
wouldn't be able to speak in front of
groups
if i didn't really want to
become a podcaster and like get my
message out
i'd probably still be super afraid to
put out any audio or video content and
so it's
you know it's all about creating
leverage right like if we create enough
like we do this is another kind of tony
thing is
everything that people do is to either
move towards pleasure or away from pain
for me
my the pleasure that i was seeking was
to be a crossfit coach that's what i
wanted and so that
overrode the amount of pain that i would
feel
or also i would feel a lot of pain if i
didn't do that right
and so it's all about like
there's on both sides of the spectrum
like in the middle is neutral right and
say on one side you have that pain
other side you have that pleasure
and it's
moving away from that middle
like either you're really trying hard to
avoid pain or you're really trying hard
to gain some sort of pleasure
at a certain point you kind of hit that
like
that point where you're going to take
action where the leverage is high enough
and so creating those kind of situations
where
you know i was like
and i'm scared to podcast but
it's going to hurt a lot more if in a
bunch of years i look back with regret
and say man i should have done that
yeah yeah it's like creating the these
situations to get leverage on yourself
either creating pain or
where you build up the other side like
most people are more motivated by pain
like most people will do a lot more to
avoid pain than they will to gain
pleasure
like you ask someone
would they rather
earn an extra thousand dollars or lose a
thousand dollars like much more people
are like
oh i'd rather uh
not lose a thousand dollars even though
it's the same amount of money right
but people are
much more afraid to lose than they are
willing to go and gain and so it's funny
i i see it almost in like i'll talk this
is
i guess it's related but like fantasy
football
play but
people you propose trades and people in
fantasy football are like
9 out of 10 of them are so afraid to do
trades because they think oh what if i
trade my guy
and then he starts doing well
right versus like instead of thinking
like oh what's the upside of the sky
that i'm getting and so most people
would rather stay put
than kind of take that that upside risk
you know what i'm saying like most
people try to minimize the downside
rather than
maximize the upside
yeah yeah it kind of reminds me of this
uh uh have you read any simon cynic
he's a he's a motivational teacher yeah
he's a leader um
he has a
yes start with why exactly it might be
either in that or maybe it's leaders e
last but one of his books or one of his
talks he uh he talks about he had the
situation at the end of something or
maybe a race or something there was a
line for bagels and he was with his
friend and he was like oh let's go get
free bagels but there was a line and his
friend's like no i don't i don't want to
wait in the line and he's thinking but
we get bagels if we if we wait in the
line you know and so and he was
basically pointing out some people see
the line and some people see the bagels
you know and so and so you've got to
look at what do i want to get what's my
end goal you've got to look at your your
kind of long term self over your short
term comforts because it's very easy to
see the big line right there and it's
hard to get started but if you if you
focus on
okay yes i'm gonna have to wait in this
line to get to bagel or yes i'm gonna
have to learn how to stumble over my
words and be a little bit better at
public speaking if i want to get to this
podcast and be a podcaster so yeah i
think that i think that's great great
info there um pushing against that
uncomfortability and then also what do
you
do you have any advice for people um
trying to trying to focus more on their
long-term goals rather than their
short-term comforts
that's it's funny that's exactly what i
was gonna say next uh
because it's so related you know like
i thought
i'm a very like future oriented person
like i have a
i know where i want to go
and
i don't know exactly how i'm going to
get there but i know that like
every decision that i make needs to lead
towards that end goal
not today's comfort because often times
are the opposite thing right so
i could have either said well i don't
want to
be uncomfortable today with
putting my voice out there
or i don't want to feel that regret in
the future like long term and and not
achieve my goals and so it's
if you can have a clear picture of where
you want to go in that long term
and then reverse engineer that's like
your compass that's like your end point
that's like if you have if you have a
map and you're trying to get somewhere
like you know where you want to go and
then it's like pretty obvious okay i
need to turn here i need to go there
but most people don't have that
figured out
like if you ask the average person like
what do you want in life like what's
what are you doing in 10 years most of
them are like
i don't know like they never even i hope
i have a million bucks
yeah right like oh yeah someday this
someday that and
someday typically means never unless you
have a direct plan and so
that's like step one i think for
everyone who hasn't done it is get
really really clear about
what you want out of your life in your
future because otherwise you're just
going to kind of drift and like you
don't know where the heck you're going
to end up but it's probably not going to
be
where you want if you're not intentional
about it and so
a lot of people if you ask them to do
that they say wow i really
i want a lot of money it's like okay
well how much exactly why do you want it
what are you gonna do with it like get
specific
because the mind
doesn't direct itself towards not
specific things right and so
that's why people create vision boards
and it's like you know it seems kind of
whatever sometimes but it's like there's
there's science to it
right because like the more clarity you
have the more your brain is able to kind
of
make it tangible and measurable and that
sort of stuff so
getting really clear on that i mean a
lot of people know what they don't want
a lot more than they know what they want
and so
if you know that that's a good place to
start write down okay i don't want this
i don't want that i don't like this i
don't want to be doing this
you know like a lot of people know that
they don't want to be doing their
current job in the future but they don't
know what they would rather do instead
you know and so
getting really clear on that vision
uh and there's a lot of different ways
to do that and you know one of them that
i like that i got from one of my
favorite authors mj demarco
uh
is called the 10-5-1 plan
and so basically what you do is
you create your 10-year vision where do
you want to be in 10 years
and you do it kind of category by
category you can do it however you want
i like to category my category so what
car am i driving
what's my typical day look like where am
i living how much money do i have in my
bank account who are my friends like you
can get really really dialed in with it
i think i have like 12 categories or
something like that what's my like at
that point in my life what's my hobbies
what am i learning
you know what toy am i buying myself
like that year so like you know 10 years
out i'm like i'm buying myself a
freaking like helicopter you know okay
heck yeah yeah for five years i'll buy
myself like a sweet rv but like one year
out it's like i'm buying myself a
mountain bike you know so it's like it's
all like kind of
uh in levels but you figure out that
10-year
vision get really clear on that and then
you say okay at five years where do i
need to be in all those categories to be
on the trajectory to where i want to be
in ten years
and then for your five-year you say okay
where do i need to be in one year
to be moving towards that
trajectory right and then you have your
one year and you say okay a year now i
can break that down into months so what
actions do i need to take this month
and then you can just further break it
down week and day and so everything so
you kind of use this vision as like your
guiding compass to all your decisions
and so every decision that you make
everything that you decide to do or not
do you say does this align with where
i'm trying to go
you may find that
you start moving towards one direction
you're like you know what i thought i
wanted that but i really don't
and so it's a living document it always
changes as you know as you grow and
evolve and learn more about yourself
but
there's a fine line between that like
rerouting
and quitting
like because
you know a lot of people will say i want
this and they start to take action
towards and i like oh crap like this is
a lot harder than i thought this is
going to take a lot more work and time
than i thought
and 90 of people will stop at that
they'll say you know what
i'm fine i'm happy they'll convince
themselves they're happy
and they'll say
you know that was a nice thought and i
stream but
you know
maybe i'll
accept this other smaller thing instead
you know and so there's a fine line
between redirecting and quitting
you know or adjusting the vision versus
like quitting on the vision so
i know that's a lot but that's a very
practical thing that i think so many
people can do to create that kind of
long-term vision and
you know because usually anything that
you do to kind of maximize short-term
gain or pleasure
is taken away from your odds of getting
that long-term big picture things like
they're often so at odds and
culture society teaches us to value that
like
short-term comfort you know live for the
weekends
a two-week vacation but it's like
i'm like in 10 years i want to be doing
whatever the heck i want in my life i
want to be financially blind i want to
be able to go wherever i want i want to
have like people i look up to the
authors i follow say like
i'll be hanging out with those people
like at their house
i'm going to know tony robbins on a
first name basis like you know all these
things
and uh
you know so that's that's
what motivates me and then also that
will dictate like like most people don't
have a risk tolerance because they can't
see that
you know sometimes you gotta take some
more risk or or go through uncertainty
in the beginning for a while
to get to that certain place so like
with entrepreneurship like
so many people say they want to start
their own business but then they can't
walk away from that job because
they can't
they can't stand the thought of not
having like a steady paycheck coming
security yeah
yeah and so it's like
if you're not going to take the leap now
you're probably not going to take it
later because it's only going to become
harder and harder
right especially as
you know say you have kids and you get
more commitments you get a mortgage
whatever and so it's like you know you
got to do it sooner than later because
it's never really going to get easier
and so that's that's a huge thing that
holds so many people back and
for me
i've
i've gone through a ton of like when i
went out to entrepreneurship i didn't
have any experience
and have any track record i didn't have
any connections i didn't have any
savings
i was like and i probably wouldn't do it
that same way if i did it again
because i've racked up you know a
substantial amount of credit card debt
because i'm like i'm gonna see this
through and do it right right
the leverage that i get on myself
with that long-term goal allows me to
endure the uncertainty
so i say man this sucks right now i'm
stressed definitely anxiety i don't
you know the light at the end of the
tunnel is hard to see sometimes but i'm
like i don't do this and i settle and i
go and get
what i'd call like a regular job or nine
to five or whatever where i'm kind of
capped and
i'm like there's no chance that i'm
gonna be able to live that 10-year
vision that i have planned
so having that allows you to
gain leverage on yourself in the short
term to to stick it through those tough
times
yeah dude and i think
i think of words like faith and in hope
um you know when you're when it's you
see it's obvious oh i have a lot of
credit card debt but i know that i'm
gonna get these things i know that i'm
capable of handling these things look
how far i've come already that's that's
really where i always just love bringing
in those words we throw out the the baby
with the bathwater so to say when it
comes to those those words like uh faith
and hope but i think they are important
to bring in even even into the
entrepreneur world um
i i was uh
uh
just to
make a distinction on that like
there's a difference between having hope
and faith in what you're doing
and executing on it versus just hoping
and praying right which is a lot of
people
right when it comes to like oh someday
like i
i hope this happens in my life or i hope
i have this it's like that's not a
strategy like you have to have faith and
belief
but it has to accompany
a plan of action
right because hoping and praying or like
you know people talk about law of
attraction it's like no you can't just
sit there and like a million dollars
isn't going to fall out of the sky yeah
and so you have to do that stuff to
create the belief but it's really about
the law of action like you have to have
the belief coupled with action or a plan
for it to work and so you could hope and
pray all you want but
right now unless you win the lottery
that's it's probably not going to work
for you so just a quick distinction
there
yeah no no law of attraction with a lot
of hard work definitely um i i was
thinking about you know you're talking
about our our belief systems our our
societal belief systems uh a lot of it
to even question like wait how why do i
believe what i believe and who taught me
that and is it helpful and is it
attributing to or taking away from me
getting the things that are going to
bring me joy and and be the you know be
an actualized being
uh when it comes to
that whole realm just societal beliefs i
think about
comedians for example comedians are
they're kind of the ones who are telling
the jokes that
they're funny because they're talking
about how absurd we're being or where
where we're being ridiculous as a
culture and they're perfect they're very
needed they're very necessary we need
comedians and i also think of artists
and you know
all these different realms of artistry
um not just painters but musicians and
and poets and um and singers and people
who create and just in anything artistry
they're also kind of doing that same
pushing the boundaries of what we're
supposed to be doing you know pointing
out the edges of of where we are as a
culture and what we believe
where do you find people like you
because i feel like you do fit into this
realm of you know personal development
self-help
you know
believing in yourself being positive
being not like most people thinking
differently all the things
all the categories that you may fall
into i feel like they are really
important kind of up here with the
artistry and in the um comedians
do you have any thoughts around that
like where do you see yourself or the
personal development world in this
pushing against the edges of belief
systems
yeah i got a few thoughts on that you
having like another hour or so oh hit me
man i'm open hear me
i'm all ears that's a
man that's a massive part of
what i believe you know so like not not
most people if you looked at it like a
venn diagram one side of it would be a
lot of the stuff that we're talking
about like success and being elite and
that sort of thing not most people the
other side is anti-group think so
thinking for yourself standing out from
the crowd
kind of forging your own path and so
that's a huge part of it uh
and i don't know i can't pinpoint like
one
specific time where i started to
realize that i thought differently but
i remember growing up
you know i i was homeschooled through
seventh grade like i said but i did not
want to be i want to go to school and
my mom you know she's catholic and
pretty like she's didn't want me to be
exposed to the public school system or
whatever and
i was like why this and why that and i
would always ask why
i've always been a very logical person
like i guess even since i was little
and so i'd ask why and a lot of times
whether it was her or even when i got to
school and
it was teachers or other authority
figures and a lot of times the answer
would be like because we said so i'm
like
that doesn't make any sense like that's
not an answer yeah
it's like a non-answer and so i was like
why are these like because i would
always ask that when something didn't
like add up in my head like why is this
the rule
why are we learning this right like in
high school i'm like why am i learning
pre-calculus like
i don't have no interest in this for any
reason you know and like stuff like that
it's like why aren't we learning real
life skills you know like why aren't you
learning money management and social
skills and
you know
stuff like that and so i was always like
questioning things and so
like for example
my high school was like an all guys
private high school that again i did not
want to go to
uh but
they had this one rule where if you got
caught with your cell phone like in
school or even after school like inside
the school
even the parking lot sometimes you got
five hours of detention
and i was like
why is that a rule like that doesn't
make any sense like why
why does being on your phone deserve
five hours of sitting in a room in
silence it's like yeah what
yeah like just things like that like
that's an extreme example but there's so
much that i was like what and then
i was like why does everyone go to
college even if they don't know why
they're going to college or what they
want to do and that sort of thing so
it's like i went to college
i had a great time
was it worth six figures like what i
learned not a chance i am close
i learned so much more in the few years
after college than i did
in college like through self-education
and so
i realized that
we've been taught
most like most of our lives what to
think and not how to think
and so it's like we learned in school
like don't question authority do it
follow the rules do what everyone else
does
if you
don't understand something or question
something or believe something different
like that's frowned upon right and so
all these things i'm like why is it why
is there like this narrative that
everyone is kind of gently pushed to
follow
and
i think i became more conscious of that
over the last several years like as i
got into personal development i realized
that almost everything that i was
reading or hearing from people who were
super successful or where i wanted to be
was like very different or often times
the opposite of what i had been taught
growing up
like even when it comes to like
money management or like
i'm like why is the food like i'm in the
health and fitness space i'm like why is
the food pyramid the food pyramid like
why they tell you to eat all kinds of
grains potatoes and it's like well that
was made back in the 1960s by kellogg's
yeah exactly and i'm like
follow the money right that's a whole
nother whole another can of worms but
just all of these things i'm like
there's so much that doesn't add up
that were taught
like and that most people believe and
that's why i'm you know one of the
things for not most people like that i
came up with that just kind of my
thought process even for how i came up
with it i said
most people
aren't really healthy most people aren't
really wealthy and most people aren't
really happy
so why the heck would you want to live
or think like most people really
and so like with that basic logic it's
like
oh yeah so the people who are where i
want to be that small percentage of
people who are really fit small
percentage of people who are really
wealthy small percentage of even smaller
percentage of people that are truly
happy these days
they're doing things a lot different
than the majority or than what kind of
society teaches right and so that was a
huge part of it and so now
you know i can't even
i can't even watch like mainstream media
you know like it's so there's so much
i'm like
these are for-profit companies
and again i'm not going to go too far
down the
rabbit hole here but these are
for-profit companies same same as
universities right like why are
universities
getting massively more expensive like
way more than inflation over the past 20
years right this student debt and stuff
like that and so
all of that you look back and you say
okay why are these things happening and
you say well
these big news corporations like when
you have that much power and influence
you are ripe for corruption like they're
you know donor or who who's going to
contribute the most like
almost all of them are bought in some
way right like or paid for by special
and like so they have to you know cater
to whoever's kind of funding them
and all this stuff and it's like
so are there motives
really to
be honest and truthful it's like no
because that doesn't get eyeballs like
what gets eyeballs which makes them
money is controversy and
you know people
like the human mind
is
instinctively geared towards focusing on
danger so when we see bad news we think
danger and this was a survival mechanism
for most of history
but now
they've kind of taken advantage of that
and used it because they know that like
people will read about bad news or pay
attention to bad news a lot more than
good news or the truth and so like we'll
say whatever kind of most ridiculous
thing is to get the most attention
because
you know even if they don't want to
they're going to lose viewers to their
competitors if they don't
right so they've kind of created this
like vicious cycle of competition with
like who can
who can get the most eyeballs and like
at this point
you know
like with ai with all the data they have
it's like they know exactly what
triggers to pull and what kind of stuff
to so it's just
there's no way to ever see it ending or
to have it be like oh here's the news
because like we have you
your best interest in mind
you know
like you you turn on the news and you
think the world's falling apart you know
and in some ways it might be but
you know when you don't ever see any
good and people see that as like their
little window into reality of like
what's going on in the outside world
it's like no you're looking at a very
small controlled
like do you see what they want you to
see version of the outside world yeah
you know
and
so like that's just one example right
and then like schools
you know why is why is there this push
to
get everyone to college you know
regardless of if you know what you want
to do or not or if you're
like i'd say 90 of degrees are
pretty much worthless like i could have
gone and became a trainer without a
strength conditioning degree pretty
easily
right like if you're in science
technology whatever then yeah that's a
different story but
you know
my sister uh one of my sisters she got a
political science degree doesn't use it
never did
she got like a applied like health in
the community or she kind of did like an
individualized major she's not using it
right now
so like a lot of these things
you you you don't need them like if you
went and got spent four years getting
like real world experience you'd
probably be
a lot further
than the beginning and they make it
really easy to get student loans
compared to any other type of loan it's
like okay
and this is again a stand-up comedian
that i saw
it was a little bit and he's like
you want to go get like a business loan
for this thing that you're making money
on and it's like okay what's your credit
what's your inventory like what are we
gonna leverage against it
and all this stuff
and it's like oh i can't get a loan for
like 10 grand it's like and then they go
to a college student and it's like
oh okay so you have no skills you're 18.
uh you're gonna come out and and all
this debt yeah okay here
you're like all the money you could want
60k easy yeah yeah yeah and so it's
creating this like debt society and they
they want that because when people are
in debt
obviously
if their government loans the government
makes money on them and they can't be
forgiven through bankruptcy or anything
like that right student loans
and then also
it forces people to keep working and
keep
giving back in taxes to the system so
it's all just like it's this big kind of
manufactured like
system that they or the higher up
whatever you want to call it
have kind of manufactured
and a lot of people buy into it right
and that's why so many people are stuck
in this rat race and can't retire until
they're 60 and i'm like
the idea
of working
40 50 hours a week for like a vast
majority of your life like what kind of
life is that you know and most people
never think twice about it
so
right i could keep granting and ranting
on this stuff dude no yeah i'm totally
with you i totally agree on a lot of
this stuff it's i i really think of it
as capitalism is now just watching
itself eat its own tail and we're like
well this it's what you do in in our
generation and people who think a little
bit outside the box are saying hey
there's no long-term benefits of this
this has like ran its course we need to
be doing something differently why are
you continuing doing it um and i think
that you know
kind of coming back to the to the
question that i was asking is i think
this realm of self-development this
realm of of bettering ourselves in this
realm of um you know
breaking the group think in whichever
ways we can do you know a lot of times
through podcast conversations um
uh or being in the in these groups to
empower one another
is is a good way for us to all think
kind of outside of the box and i think
more and more it's not going to sound as
woo-woo and as um
as you know
crazy conspiracy theory person when
we're when we're challenging the status
quo when more and more people start to
understand it and i feel that our
generation i think you're are you
millennial are you around my age around
30s
yeah it'll be i'll be 30 this month
oh cool hey happy early birthday um i'll
be 30 in just a few short months after
that um but yeah i do kind of see our
we're the tail end of millennials you
know like not too much younger than us
as a is gen z and the people who have
grown up with cell phones and
they're growing up
wanting their own piece of something you
know you look at dudes like logan paul
and jake paul and stuff is there a lot
of what they do is totally outlandish
but it's also this huge
you know the lighthouse siren to me of
this whole generation coming up of
people who are going to build their own
stuff they're going to do their own
thing they're going to find their own
ways of of winning like i i just i don't
see a lot of the younger people paying
for college in the ways that people our
age and older have so i just think it's
going to be
it's a huge change and i do see
uh you know people like you
really kind of
um
maybe not leading the charge but you're
definitely up there in in a strange way
like it's very important what you guys
are doing it's empowering the individual
and not just holding up a
instruction booklet of read these here's
what you do here's how you live what
life and you'll by the time you're 40
you'll have a white picket fence and you
can retire and drink margaritas until
you fall over on the beach
yeah so so it's important what you do
man
thank you thank you i think everything
goes in cycles right like if you look at
50 years ago
a college degree was pretty rare you
know because
you know college was technically a lot
more affordable than it is now even
compared to inflation but
you know it was like
certain people went to college otherwise
a lot of people were blue collar they
got their careers they stayed with a
company for a long time
and then we saw this evolution of like
more and more people go to college now
that's the norm and now in the future
you're going to see people start to
realize and start to realize already
that
college doesn't guarantee like a success
or career afterwards and so then you're
going to see this it's all kind of like
it goes cyclically right
and
you know right now they're still trying
to kind of
the narrative is still share that like
you go to school you get good grades you
get a degree you get a career you get a
house and that's
you know what you do you know but that's
that's not how it works anymore like so
many more people are self-employed
a lot of people
don't really need the big house they
want freedom they want to be able to
travel they want to be able to pursue
what they want and so
i think we're seeing like you said this
big shift away from kind of the way
things have been for the last
you know since our
our parents in the 50s and 60s like how
it's kind of been
um
so it's interesting to see for sure
but it's like it's interesting too
because you've also seen like people
grew up like our parents like reading
the newspaper watching the news each day
and for it for the most part like you
could trust the news back then like
there wasn't this whole like fake news
and bias and all and like division like
there is now so it's like it's really
interesting to see that cross section of
all these things that are shifting
yeah
no it's it's a it's you know equatable
to madness in a lot of ways really as
we're trying to tell our grandparents no
it's that's not the only truth anymore
and the young kids are not even like
reading any of it listening to any of it
there's it is this strange time that we
are in um but i i think that we'll come
out on the other side of it a lot more
intelligent as um you know i think maybe
we can empower the group think to
actually be a little more intellectual
that would be nice uh with some time i
had a uh
my i was a theater kid amongst many
other things growing up in in high
school
and my favorite drama teacher would
always say dare to be different
and it's it's this such simple thing and
you can broadly apply it to so many
different things but it really it sparks
right here and i think that it is very
important just that's that first thing
is dare to be different dare to you know
question the status quo and really think
what what are my beliefs getting me who
taught them to me um how are they
helping me out can i find some other
ways to help myself out is there things
that i'm neglecting that i could be
teaching myself you know
all these things so
bradley we are getting up here in time
um
i am i'm a single man but i definitely
want to help out my homies my listeners
with
um relationships long-term relationships
so i hate to to crunch you into this
like give me an elevator pitch of it but
can you give me just like a few minutes
of what's like some some optimum um you
know
like
advice that you might give to people in
relationships because you are a
relationship coach as well like what do
you find often what's something that's
very common um you know most bang for
our buck here
yeah so there's two sides to that
there's the side of
like you're talking to the single guys
which is
me in the past and then you're talking
to people who are in long-term
relationships and so
the principles differ a little bit uh
but
kind of like what we've been talking
about i try to wake people up to all
these misconceptions that people have
about relationships about dating and
like we talked about all these things
with the news in school and stuff but
like
when it comes to relationships and
dating like i think hollywood
has actually put a lot of ideas into our
minds that aren't necessarily true that
like
oh if you're like a really nice guy
eventually she'll dump the [__] and
ride off into the sunset with you right
and then all these nice guys are like
why isn't it working that way
you know like i'm doing all these
romantic gestures and then
she's still just you know with this
other douchebag right and uh
so that's like one thing the other thing
is that
this idea of a soulmate that once you
find your soulmate or the right person
that everything clicks and
that's that's what matters and that's
right
well that matters for maybe like six
months to initially getting to know each
other period but then beyond that
you know it's like people think
people know that when it comes to health
and fitness that if you don't work out
you get out of shape
right people know that if you
stop working you don't make money in
your career go south
but people think that they get into a
relationship and if it's the right
person
that that takes care of everything yeah
you don't do anything
you don't do anything and so you really
see
and every once in a while you'll have
that odd couple that just kind of works
you know and they can get away with that
but that's like
the rare rare exception like most
people need to work at it otherwise
as you evolve and change as a person
like
that one little
thing that your partner does that you
used to think was cute now annoys the
heck out of you and stuff like that and
so
you know because it was new
but like those things can build over
time resentment builds
things that you
like we're taught that oh we don't want
to hurt our partner we don't want to
make them feel bad and so we'll hold
back a lot of things that need to be
said for fear of hurting their feelings
even though like those things need to be
worked through
and so like the more you ignore them
then like that resentment can build up
and the communication blocks happen and
then
one thing leads to another and so
there's this idea of relationship
development that i like to share which
is
work on your relationship with your
partner the same way that you guys work
on your health the same way that you
talk about finances whatever
like so
me and my fiance
we don't stick up like we don't
do it every month but we try to pick
some sort of relationship focused book
and read it and then kind of discuss it
together we try to
like come back to like the love
languages get each other just a random
gift
hearing it just because you know it
doesn't have to be a special occasion
you know little things like that making
sure that you know a lot of people have
a date night but
even if you have a date night just
having a night where you're together and
you're fully present like no phones
right that's a big thing these days
uh
making sure we we go away on little
trips together every so often right and
i know that gets harder and when you
have kids and all that kind of stuff but
making making it a priority because if
you don't work these things into your
life like you do go into the gym or
going to work or whatever like it's
going to slide it's going to get
neglected and then
we got half over half the couples you
know marriages ended in divorce now and
so
you have to work on these things and so
trying to change that misconception that
like yeah your soulmate that's cool and
all that but that's like a small piece
of the picture right and then the whole
other side which i'm passionate about
too is like for dudes like you're
talking about
uh
really for me like so we've been
together over six years me and my fiance
and
for the first probably four four and a
half
you know things were rocky at times we
didn't really communicate on like a deep
level
and we had a lot of clashes and that was
because i didn't really have an
understanding
of what true masculinity meant
polarity
so
you know we grow up thinking that
masculinity is an appearance
like
jacked tattoos drives a pickup truck
like that's masculine right or like as a
female like you wear pink and long
blonde hair and makeup and whatever but
what they are is they're actually kind
of energies or states of being
and so you could have the most masculine
look in the world but it but you could
be doing feminine traits right like the
simple example is your your girlfriend
says hey where do you want to go eat and
you say i don't know where you want to
go eat and it just goes back and forth
she's looking for you to make the
decision and say we're going here
and then she says okay he's focused he
knows what he wants he knows where he's
going
and
that's what they want right and then
they can relax and be kind of more
feminine and
whatever and so understanding just a lot
of those little dynamics about like what
it really means to be masculine like
having a strong presence not being
thrown off not
you know i would
we'd get into arguments i would kind of
withdraw and be quiet and i try and be a
pleaser like that's the biggest thing
right when you talk about nice guys like
you know pleaser like oh always
deferring to what she wants and it's
like no she's like if she's a feminine
woman
and obviously it exists all over the
spectrum like you can have a masculine
woman
with a feminine man and it can work
whereas that balance is in the middle
and so but if you have a feminine woman
and you're kind of exhibiting feminine
qualities
you get thrown off that middle of
polarity and then there's clashes or
vice versa you'd be a masculine dude but
then
you know if your fiance say is a
or a fiance but your girlfriend is a
like an entrepreneur and she has to have
that hardcore focus like go go go
like at work or whatever she's working
on and then brings that home then there
could be another clash there and so it's
learning to kind of find this balance in
the middle
and understanding like for me
i was kind of again being that pleaser
and so she would have to take on this
more masculine role and it would throw
her off and she'd be and you know
and it's it's always shifting and
balancing but if you're off of your
natural set point for too long
things start to go south right you start
to know
and so it's learning to understand that
and once i
one book i would recommend is the way of
the superior man by david daida and that
book gave me so many light bulb moments
understanding like oh
she
is all mad about this thing and i'm like
why is she mad about this little thing
it's like no she's mad about this that
and the other thing that happened over
the last few weeks and it's just coming
out now because of this little thing
right so understanding like a lot of
those things and
and uh
being able to stay like strong and
present in an argument and not be thrown
off emotionally by her a whole lot and
like her knowing that you're not going
anywhere that you have your like all
these things
really started to change our dynamic and
help me understand that i think that
that's
so missed
uh by most people growing up because
unless they had like a strong father
figure that kind of exhibited these
things
you know obviously
you know
again there's a lot more i could go into
but i'll leave it at that right
excellent man no i think that was all
really good and i i do agree there's
like where do we where do we learn this
stuff we think we i would hate for
anybody to see this as any sort of
defeat or like you're lesser than or
like your relationship is failing so now
you need you need help and that makes
you wait like it's not like that it was
these are real things that are our world
our technology our everything has
changed and we've got to change with it
um and we've got a you know and
we could relearn these when you when you
say words like masculine and feminine
like i already know of the the
annotations that come with that you know
we do think of this yeah the other
stereotypes um and we even in kind of
the spirituality world it is um it's
just a lot more in-depth and kind of
hard to reach but if you simplify it
into
you know hey this is a feminine thing
that she's doing by hinting at these
things and you need to uptake your
masculine and listen in these ways it it
helps make make sense of it all um
yeah i do i think all great stuff we are
getting up here in time though so let's
uh let's round the corner my friend
let's uh let's give everybody a little
bit uh of your
like what do you got going on right now
what are you working on where can we
find all of your info where can we
listen to your podcast give us
the whole lowdown on bradley roth
you got it yeah uh not most people is
the podcast
you can find it on all of the major
streaming platforms if you just search
it or i actually just launched the
website a few days ago at
notmostpeople.net you can find kind of
everything not most people there it's a
podcast right now but the vision is to
create a community uh
you know eventually have blogs have
courses
apparel everything so this is just kind
of like the starting point so for
everything in one spot not most
people.net and then
in terms of personally probably the best
way is to just connect on instagram
which is at bradley underscore roth uh
my relationship site is in the works
right now uh still
but uh
excited about that uh and i'll start
i'll be putting out a lot more content
around that so
not most people.net and
probably underscore roth on instagram is
probably the easiest way to get in touch
cool cool wonderful and just as someone
who has i've been listening to your
podcast a little bit
timeless totally like you don't have to
wait for the newest episode he's got
already has a couple of really great
episodes from what i thumbed through um
i i definitely enjoy podcast i'm gonna
i'm i'm gonna be a normal listener i
think bradley so um i appreciate you
doing everything that you do i
appreciate your time in in opening up
and expressing yourself and talking
about all these things and answering my
really long-winded questions
one one last thing before we send it off
i like to to try to find some sort of
interesting
question at the end here's one that i
like to ask a lot
um
if you had to give
if you had to answer
what does the world need more of right
now what would you say
that's a good one um
yeah
it's funny because i have a question
that i ask everyone too on my podcast
[Music]
and now i know what it feels like to be
stumped but i have a dog
i feel like
my answer goes back to kind of what we
said if if we could
start
teaching people
like those soft skills those that
understanding of basic psychology and
stuff like that at a younger age and
understanding behavior and how the mind
works on like a basic level
like i said i think that
can solve a lot of problems um because
otherwise we're driven by
like we don't understand our actions we
don't understand other people's actions
and so that causes us to react
emotionally and as you've seen
emotional reactions
versus emotional like you can emotions
great serves a purpose but having
responses
right
versus being like what we call triggered
uh
it doesn't leave room
to
find middle ground
so until people
find have this ability to kind of
question things or to think for
themselves
or to have logical conversations
it's gonna be really hard to bridge all
these divisions that we're seeing
and
so i think a little more a little more
understanding of human behavior and of
ourselves
yeah he's super helpful
yeah dude i really love that answer i i
totally agree i think just the amount of
of gold that's just just below the
surface you know you just you just
really don't have to learn you don't
have to make it your life's purpose and
you know read books for the next 35
years about psychology i just diving
into it a little bit learning how you
work learning how other people work
teaching our young people how it works
from a young age like you said uh yeah
it's just this subtle thing but it
really starts to shape your reality and
how you perceive yourself in your
internal dialogue as well as your
external conversations with one another
yeah being able to uh
not suppress your emotions but learning
to control them and not have them
control you
is huge so that that ability to you know
master your emotions at least on a basic
level
uh
is huge if i were to sum it up yeah yeah
it's massive absolutely all right man
hey i appreciate you again this was a
great conversation thanks for uh giving
your time again
listeners take care of yourselves if you
aren't doing mobility before your
workouts what are you doing you're crazy
if you aren't drinking a ton of water if
you're listening to this right now and
you haven't drank water today you're out
of your mind stop what you're doing
pause this or keep listening and go get
some water stretch take care of yourself
love yourself check out bradley roth
i'll include in the in the notes some
links to his website and whatnot bradley
once again thank you man i hope you have
a good rest of your day too thank you so
much really enjoyed this conversation
yeah yeah take care
[Music]
man at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
uh
knowledge is power
[Music]
you